Hating on your girl, baby, hating on your girl.
Now there's no volume, so y'all cannot hear me.
Can you hear me? Can you hear me? Can you hear me? Can you hear me? Can you hear me?
Can you hear me? Can you hear me? Can you hear me? Can you hear me?
All right. You can hear me. Sheesh.
Okay. Welcome back.
uh this is what would your ancestors say and it is a little series that I started to
initially I started it to help uh spread the word about my project what would the ancestors say
but honestly it's been a really dope exercise and engaging with just folks about what their
ancestors are who their ancestors are what they would think about where we are where we're going
etc I look crazy like I look actually crazy like I look tired and overweight I look tired and
overweight and that's just really what it is
like struggle all right anywho so my show what would the ancestors say is happening on live stream
in Los Angeles on November 8th if you are in Los Angeles you can get tickets as well as a signs
book and meet and greet at amandaseals.com if you are not in LA you can get your tickets for the live
stream at um at amandaseals.com you can also get the bundle which is the live stream ticket and the book
at amandaseals.com this is of course you know I believe that this is a show that like really
will enrich you enliven you etc so go over to amandaseals.com get your tickets
in the book now if you want to see a little little uh snippet let's check it out I believe that if
white folks do not build altars on Juneteenth they should be haunted shout out to everyone who's
already purchased their tickets I really do appreciate you and um you know this is uh
this is really this is the first completely independent venture um and I say completely
independent because the last time that I did a live stream of this nature I had a job
I had a job um I don't have a job no more I am completely independent and work for myself
and it really is um you know you guys support that is uh how I exist so even if you perhaps
don't have the funds but you work for an organization that may benefit from having these books uh I hope
you'll reach out because we are going to be selling uh I don't know why I'd be saying we
I am going to be selling a wholesale of the books however I want to let you know that this book will
only be available on amandaseals.com and amandalandexports.com it will also be available in bookstores but
I am not putting this book available on major corporation sites like Amazon or Barnes and Noble
etc and if you want to see some of the dopeness of the book um I this is my favorite page in the book
I ain't gonna lie to you this is my favorite page
and uh the book is filled with illustrations
um that's Frederick and the theme is that we call on our ancestors to give us guidance to give us
protection etc which is why some of the ancestors pictured are pictured with weapons right because
they're giving us guidance and protection in a number of ways here's one of our most recent
ancestors the sister Asada Shakur on the classic Motorola flip with the Glock non-milli
I drew all of these illustrations myself um and uh by the way if you want to get your Malcolm
the Malcolm drop is also available right now at amandalandexports.com if you were looking to get
the Malcolm uh bonus bundle they were sold out but there were more just put on sale and available so
get you the Malcolm bonus bundle so let's get into it um I'm definitely being shadow banned because I
don't know why there's only 149 people here so let's get into it who wants to come up tonight and talk
about their ancestors let's go to y'all I took a nap that nap took me when I told you that nap took me
out hello hello you are in the darkness yes I am I'm just putting the babies to sleep how are you
oh well then this isn't really gonna work because you're in the darkness oh dear hold on a second
don't know if you can see me it's terrible hold on I'll try and get some light on are you in
Liverpool no no I'm in Scotland in Scotland yeah hold on you'll be I'm just gonna put the back
light on I'm not putting the bedroom light on you see me hi hello um you're in Scotland yeah oh just
don't mind the patches on the ceiling I'm doing paint patches and I'm trying to do a bit of a
um bit of a renovation thing DIY going on but um I just wanted to be very quick on the phone
and just speak very quickly without waking everybody up but um I've been trying to come
on your life for a wee while I've been listening to everything you're saying the guy yesterday was
so fabulous and he was so um uh he was so like what's the words he was so like I was like where
has he been I wish I met somebody like him so well articulated everything and just fabulous anyway
I got to me and I was thinking a lot and I was like what about my ancestors
and I'm born and brought up in Scotland um Glasgow but my parents are back from Kashmir Pakistan
and my grandparents were obviously from there as well but they had all immigrated over here
um I think my dad was about seven years old when he arrived with his parents
and then my mother after she was married to him and all the rest of it
but now that I'm speaking about this I was brought up just as a point of conversation
um what would my ancestors say just about our communication and language alone that's all
because I'm not very well articulated and I don't deep things very often but I get confused at the
whole lot of it and I'm thinking about it and I'm thinking often when I'm growing up my mum's like
you have to learn how to speak Urdu because you can't speak you won't know how to talk to your
relatives back home etc etc and that's been drilled into us and I'm very well at speaking fluent Urdu now
just as an example whereas when I speak to my cousins they speak back to me in English
so you'll speak so they understand Urdu yeah yeah of course they've been brought up as well but they'll
make it a point to speak to me in English and they will go out their way to speak only English now
they will not speak Urdu because they think that's a taint on their identity
so they've all went away and as I said I'm not academic I've not been educated I went to
and she resigned school and dropped out decided to get married have a family raising my kids now
and whenever I speak to my cousins back home they'll speak English and they make sure
that I know because I'm born and brought up here that I know that they know how to speak English
and that Urdu is not a big deal Urdu is not a thing and and I was just thinking why was it drilled into me
why was it drilled into me I think if I'll be very honest with you I think
it's a long-winded colonialism they've been drilled and brought up to say you can't have your identity
any longer because it's not worth anything yeah now when we're at school and things learning
whatever we're learning we don't learn a lot of history about Pakistan I go out my way to learn it
I go out my way to learn what the history is and I just two I would say maybe three generations back
they were so proud of where they were from even they had no money small villages but they were proud
of their identity they were proud of their caste they were proud of their parents their grandparents
the great grandparents they had family trees I ask my dad now he doesn't know
he doesn't know and I've got out my way to go back the ways and learning how to where I came from
everything people look at me and they say Scottish oh my god how can you be Scottish we had this whole
debate on another live I think it was on TikTok and it was like an Afghani Pakistani woman you're not
Scottish and I thought well just because I've got brown hair and black brown hair black hair and
brown skin doesn't mean I'm not Scottish I was born here I was brought up here I speak like Scots
I do like the Scots just according to within the fold of my religion which is Islam so I won't go
out my way I need ham and pork right but I'm gonna you know what I mean it's just right you're not eating
haggis but yeah if haggis was halal it'd be fine right it'd be fine but it's not to my taste but anyway
you're a Pakistani girl but you don't believe in yourself girl and I'm like I'm going out my way
to learn my heritage I feel I'm Scottish because I was born if I was to go off to Mars marry somebody
we're we're on Mars and we have children on Mars are they not Martians like hello I don't say I'm not
I don't say I'm not Pakistani I'm not I do right I say I'm Scottish yeah and you know I just want you
to know you keep saying you're not educated yes I mean you may not have gone to school but you are
an intellectual I try you know like that's the thing being educated is one thing I know many
educated people that are not intellectual so know that they don't honestly see when I sometimes I
speak to somebody they've got these big fancy degrees right and whatever is in master's and PhDs
but when I speak to them within about I would say about 11 minutes I'm like you're not my person
because all they do is talk about a piece of paper and I'm like do you not have your own identity
and as much as I respect all the work that you've done that's gone into it I would question if your
common sense matches up and it almost doesn't it rarely oh my god it's freezing here by the I know
it's autumn but we're so cold we're all bundled up in bed no so are you are you teaching your kids
yeah I speak to them in Urdu and I do think I have to make a point to for them to be able to
communicate with their relatives amongst that I do tell them about Pakistan I tell them they're good
about it they're too young to understand the bad about it just now but that's with everything
it's a safety thing up here in Scotland I would tell them the good and bad as well
we've got like protests going on we have to make them aware of that as well
going to school just in general looking out for them they're quite young because you have to watch
your language and how you articulate it and but as they grow up I'm gonna have to tell them the truth
as well about the ugliness of this world what would you say what would your what would your ancestors
say do you think about the ugliness of this world particularly where my parents are from
and my grandparents are from they would be very upset they would be like why are you losing your
mother tongue for example I'm not I'm just speaking about the language right now why are you losing your
mother tongue um just to show up or show off you're catching up to some I hate to say it but you're
catching up to say well some white man because somebody told you you can't speak or do in our
university anymore you make a point to not speak or do ever again when you're in that country you
wear those clothes your grandparents are from there you buried your great grandparents there you know
you they were all poor or rich or whatever at the same time as all of that they grew what they had
from the ground they consumed it they learned they were strong um they were proud people and within
maybe two generations it's all gone two generations is all it took and it's taking me somebody all
across to the other side of the world born on the other side of the world my mum to be so strict with
it for me to be questioning everybody where why are their parents not making them for example
they stick toward why are they getting forced into speaking english a lot of the universities in
pakistan as well have been pumped with the american dollar and the curriculum goes with that as well then
so it may not necessarily be what they actually uh the parents actually stand for but it's something to
because we're paying money to get admissions into these universities paying their fees etc etc you will
follow and you will comply and one of them rules maybe we don't want to speak or do and that's just a
small example but there's plenty of examples and this is what makes me think about our heritage and
our ancestors like why they would never be let alone proud they would never even accept that
they would be accepting of other cultures yeah but they wouldn't be accepting of the
disassociation disassociation if you want to call it that or the wiping out of your own culture
your own roots yeah you're just stripping it away and the young today when i speak to them
no problem with that at all don't even think twice because they're after that piece of paper
that's going to make them that yeah that's it well you know you said that your mom
made sure that you knew or do so that you could talk to the people at to your relatives at home
and i would add that um in the in the constant quest to reconnect to the ancestral knowledge that
has come before us and that these folks continue to try to strip from us that you you speak to your
ancestors in or do like i feel like that's like a a practice like i feel like there's an exercise there
yes of course and sometimes what happens is a lot of the times when i was a teenager particularly
when i was learning when your head's a mess i couldn't articulate myself you know do it was
always just cussing and sweating but that's the way you learn i guess and i was and i'm just thinking
about it even now my children are younger they go to primary school what have you they say oh mom
some so-and-so say the f word they don't stay there so and i'm like okay i never make it a big deal
oh my god there's such and such make no you're not just i don't make that a big deal because
the more attention you give to the negative the more it manifests and they literally don't care
if i cuss sometimes i'll be like bump my foot somewhere i'll be like oh look are you okay mom
did that really hurt just goes over their head i think that's also scottish though that's the scottish in
you because the scott's curse like a mug oh 100 percent oh we're very colorful when it comes to
it and you know that you know you're gonna you'll understand exactly what we're saying well a good
friend of mine moved to grita like 20 years ago but he is scottish but his parents are punjabi
and um so but he's a but to your point he is punjabi and scottish like he's very scottish
you know so well thank you so much go ahead you hear it you definitely hear it when we're speaking
but every time i've gone on a live and i've showed up i look a mess right now to be honest but usually
i've got a bit of makeup on and stuff i look presentable right it's just bedtime just now
um usually when i'm coming on everybody expects me to have a different kind of thick accent
and then i'll have a i have a different kind of thick accent you can't understand what's going on
and i'm like just take it a minute let it process yeah let it process and then we can conversate
but it takes a wee second to get there but anyway i was just thinking about the ancestral
language in particular um because the other guy yesterday he basically made up his own language
and it was fabulous and i was like why i'm just sitting here like a dumb dumb like i'm not going
to put any brakes on anything i'm going to be full throttle with the scottish and urdu if my kids want
to throw in french and spanish in there they can do that you know it's fine but communication is what
it's going to land on i think and i agree i love i love the connectivity that you made to yesterday
for those of y'all who who weren't on uh the show yesterday what would your ancestors say
we had a brother on travis sankofo who was blowing all of our minds because like a good 15 minutes into
the conversation he just drops that he's like created his own spiritual practice that has a language
attached to it that him and his children communicate with and he taught us how to spell tuzazi
which is t-e-x-y-z and y and i mean it was but it was so enriching yeah and to your point the
language was an integral part of the spiritual practice because the words themselves were words
of love and words of community and togetherness um in a way that that doesn't exist particularly in
english so i hear you so a lot of stuff if you if you listen to him when he said a lot of stuff
doesn't uh reciprocate in english translate in english he's 100 right yeah because i can think
of a hundred different words in arabic that i've got root words then root words and then the causes
for it and what it could possibly mean one word can mean a thousand languages i think it's fabulous
because we just say shut up and you know exactly what that means right but then you can see it in
a much more pleasant way what have you in arabic and ud and stuff like that and i just thought see
where that's where he hit the nail on the head straight away when he said basically the english
language won't translate to what he's actually trying to articulate yeah um so thank you for
articulating your uh your ancestry and how language plays a role in that and um i love that i love
that people here got to experience a visual a vision of intersectionality yeah thank you so much
for taking the call amanda no we are very very nice day and very nice live and everything you're
doing such a good job honestly so proud of you i'm so happy you're here thank you wait i didn't catch
your name what's your name my name is saba oh listen to this right talking about articulation and
translation my name is saba raja that's my second name and if you translate it into english it means
don king and i was like well the frizzy hairs they are but i'm not that older i'm not that loud
it's not that kind of don king as don d-a-w-n like the female yeah and then raja raja is raja
raja is boss so yeah you have a great evening since it's evening is it wait what time is it over
there it's exactly 1 30 a.m oh my gosh go to sleep i've been on these lives for like every day and
i'm like i just need to see amanda i've got a team baby so she's up and down honestly honestly
well you have a good night and good luck with the renovation thank you so much here we go
manifesting all of it yes inshallah speak to you soon take care my lovely yes inshallah
yes this is what happens here on what would your ancestors say we get to speak to people from all
over the globe about their ancestry how dope is that i feel so lucky to be in community with you all
in this way um i know that we talk about politics all the time i know that we talk about you know
community all the time we i know that we are we of course are in a time i also feel like we have to
continue to be enriched in these ways because they are an integral part of figuring our way out through
this time so thank you to um to sabaraja for joining us and i will of course put her at and again
if you missed yesterday's what would the what would your ancestors say please make sure you check it out
if you're just joining us this is what would your ancestors say where i bring people on the live to talk
about their ancestry who their ancestors were who they think they were who they may know they are
what do they feel their ancestors would say about where we are about where they're going about where
they where they are what type of ancestor do you want to be and this is all attached to um also my book
what would the ancestors say which is going to be coming out on november 8th along with a live stream
performance of the text and what would the ancestors say is really my creative artistic expression of
looking at where we are and where we could possibly be going through the eyes of those who have come
before us and uh just so you also know i will be in dc on sunday at uh the national mall joined with
a bunch of other intellectual scholar scholars professors teachers and we will be doing a
teach-in a free teach-in on the mall in solidarity and in support of history and museums and you can
catch me i'll be there between noon and 1 30 um doing a presentation on what would the ancestors say
so you can go to um just show up it's going to be free so just show up but if you want to support
the work that i'm doing uh with the live show and the live stream make sure you go to amandaseals.com
and you can get your tickets to the live stream if you are in los angeles you can actually get your
tickets to be in studio and uh we have packages where you can get tickets to be in studio also you
can get the live stream with a signed copy so these are the things that we're doing and then also i'm
going to be doing a book tour so when i come to your city i hope that you will come through
and get your book signed and uh if we are in a bookstore i need you to also patronize that
bookstore in another way um i am really just excited to be able to be in community with you
all and uh i always feel safe i know people are always like you know you go it's dangerous out
there for you but to be quite honest i feel safe when i'm in the world with y'all because i really do
feel like how do i put it when i was in acting on in hollywood etc um like i feel like i never had
people to support me like i feel like when i tell the story of how i went to i am going to san diego
i feel like when i tell people the story of how i went to that party that emmy's party and isa ray's
publicist vanessa anderson had me removed by security guards because she didn't like me
like that was able to happen because i didn't have like people and it's because those were not
my people whereas i've had situations since then where someone came to like bring negativity to me
and the people that i was there even people i didn't know but i was there with like they like
surrounded and protected and they weren't just surrounding and protected me they were also
surrounding and protecting the the elevation and the vibration of the space like no you you you
coming in here with your negativity and we all here having a good peaceful loving time so you need to go
you need to go i went to a party the other day at a bar in brooklyn for my homegirl's birthday
and i mean you know it was very much like an after work party and i gotta tell y'all i felt safer
safer than ever in there because by the time i was there for about 30 minutes folks had come up and
been like yo what's good a minute seals yo i appreciate the work you do bop bop bop and so
whatever was if anything had popped off i feel my cats are having a time with these ikea bags
if anything had popped off i know i would have been straight i know i would have been straight
and i think that that's like it's been a really beautiful experience to be in spaces like that and to
continue to fortify spaces like that and that's what i feel like we have here there was a time
where i had to literally turn off my comments for a year i had to turn off my comments for a year on
instagram because people will come at me so wild and no one in my comments would say nothing
they would just let it rock niggas what are what are y'all doing jordi what's the what's the business
and they would just let it rock and i was like since y'all think it's okay for people to disrespect
me like this nobody gets to talk to me how about that nobody gets to talk to me but i left i came
back i left i came back and it feels like every time i've come back we have cultivated such a greater
community here and if you want an even stronger community come on over to my patreon it's five dollar
month subscription uh but we definitely be seal squatting over there so let's see uh let's bring
someone else up for tonight's edition of what would your ancestors say
hello hey israel israel okay listen um been a big fan of you since like back in the day like i was
just a little you're away are you in cali yeah yo i'm from philly though i'm from philly though i'm at
my girl crib yeah we are because i feel like it's sunny i was like why are you all right you're in the
it's cool yeah so like i've been a big fan of you since like diva speak tv like way back in the day
and i've been educating people on your words and i was a young bull like i was really like you know
i mean like yeah so to your point today what would my ancestors say i'm gonna give you a little
first first yeah what is your name ah i'm raven
i'm july 10th cancer maybe we have the same energy so we're all you already know you already
know girl let me tell you so yeah my name is raven i'm from philadelphia and i am in the navy
i just ranked up to an e5 um before i was in the navy i was i know girl i don't know either i was a
psych tech um for three years in philadelphia and i love my job but before that i went to morgan state
university studying did you have dr ball yes he was on views he was on views for amanda land
this morning it's crazy that's what i'm saying it's the energy of the world right now it's so
amazing so i i am a very educated born and raised in in west philly went to a all black university
in west philadelphia born and born and raised i'm from overbrook it's where you spent most of your
days yes honestly and truly and truly so just a little background on me like i grew up in
predominantly black spaces i was taught to love my culture to love myself i went to a hbcu that that
grew me and and i thrived in that nature um and now i decided because i had elevated in my career so
much i said well what else can't i do right i'm gonna go and be in this space that i ain't never
been in before and being in the navy i've been around different people and i've been in experiences
that i never thought i would be in in my life now and especially as a black woman right it um with
locks with locks i don't play about my i wish they would tell me something i don't play about my hair
i don't play about my hair so so my thing is um what would my ancestors say about that about the
journey that led me here and though i've only been in for two years i have excelled and people look at
me like how did you get this far you you just got here yesterday you you joined the navy before
breakfast and now you're at e5 and now you don't you made rank and you and you've done all these
things why why why why why why be in the military so i think i was at a time in my life where i was
i had a lot going on for myself financially i was very well but i wasn't doing anything and i needed
to put myself in a space of structure and i'm not sure i wasn't sure of any other way to go
okay so now that i found that structure i'm making a whole lot less but i'm doing a whole lot more
i've only been up the street around the corner in west philly but now i'm in san diego you know just
thriving right now so i have made a decision this is why i'm here to talk to you i made a decision
where i don't know if my ancestors would be proud of me they would not yes ma'am yes ma'am
and i don't know about the navy okay wait let me really no yeah talk to me talk to me sister
talk to me auntie i think our ancestors are always proud of our our self-awareness right are always a
proud are always proud of our consciousness and our bravery right and our courage and you
are presenting yourself as somebody who you know is thoughtful about like the path that you take right
like you're not just doing stuff or whatever like you you know you're not just like fly by night it
doesn't sound like you're that kind of person at all um i do think though that what has happened
for so many of us is that we've been propagandized so far out of the truth of our ancestors experiences
and out of the necessity for us to continue their work that we we have been somewhat tricked into
um going down paths that we think are radical and that we think are a continuance of them but that in
actuality are a um they're essentially a misdirect to actually de-radicalize us right so for instance
like the military as it is a part of the united states the military is an imperial complex like
its literal purpose is to continue the ability for the united states to suppress repress and steal
right from the rest of the world like that it is it's it's presented to us and to my understanding
because my ex was a navy man um it's presented as no like you are here to preserve the work of the
united states you know in in in liberating but when we get to the truth about it we also understand that
that was the same language that was used in addition in in relation to our ancestors oh we're liberating
you from your gods we're liberating you from your language we're liberating you from your savagery etc etc
when what we're actually doing is we are commodifying you into a thing that we can use
right um and and we're disconnecting you from that which protects you from us exactly i feel i feel that
that's exactly what has happened to me here and in a lot of ways when i think of my ancestors when i
think of like okay what am i trying to channel in order to get through the day because i am faced with
a lot of adversity just being a black woman a queer woman a masculine presenting woman these are
things every day that i am constantly being attacked on so when i think of my ancestors i'm asking
them for ways of protection for ways of understanding and i think that because especially
to what you just said just now is that they are trying to remove me from that i'm trying to be
a radical within a system where i they don't need they don't want me here mr hackstaff don't want me here
it's also um it's also like not really possible like the system because the system is not
what it is because of just people like it's it's the system is what it is because it's a framework
that has been put in place and upheld beyond just like oh this guy thinks like this and so now we all
think like this like it's a deep-seated culture um you know like we all know that the military is a
culture like there is an actual way of life and existence it's just like prison there's a culture in
prison like when you go into that space there's a whole different way of behaving if you want to
you know thrive survive etc than in other spaces i mean shit hollywood baby is exactly i understand um
however what i would say is that a lot of us have been trained to not listen to our intuition
we have been trained to not trust our intuition um we've been trained to kind of like doubt ourselves
because what we're thinking in our souls can't possibly be it it must be our trauma or it must
be our sensitivity or it must be you know our imposter syndrome blah blah blah blah blah like we come
all these things when sometimes it's just as basic as like nigga get out of there
my mama texted me right now you need to go jeez you tell me right now i said mom i'm on the
library i can't i can't do that i know you're watching but yeah you're right sometimes it really
is that and then you and then you're like yeah how am i supposed to do that and now you're like
i'm in a grocery store talking to myself but like sometimes it beats like that you know
my neighborhood has come to understand you're gonna see me walking the dog talking to myself
i'm trying to really get clear and we don't talk to our we don't talk to ourselves enough about what
we're trying to figure out and i feel like when i'm talking to myself i am actually talking to a
whole connectivity and network of ancestors that i am in touch with right and so like that's why like
with what would the ancestors say they're all on phones because the idea is that like we're calling
on our ancestors and we're on it we're on a main line and like you're in san diego my meditation
by the water is always bring me forward yes bring me forward bring me forward so like the water for
me you are a cancer water is our guide and um i will just never forget that when my my ex and i broke up
i like went to belize and i like was able to heal everything and i just remember being on the phone
with lauren london and she was like girl you took your troubles to the waters oh hey
yes she did so i'm telling people like take your troubles to waters
yes i think that was my next question to you is that you know this is like this has been like my
first few steps um especially since you started this and it's been so helpful to me um just to ask
this question constantly and try to call on them but like what would my first steps be and i think
you just gave it to me it was just like sit by the water and talk you know talk to my ancestors
through that you know talk to the to the people that that have my back because and and where i'm at
right now where the people i gotta see every day they ain't got it whether they look like me or not
they ain't got it you know i mean and i think many of us feel that our only way to be in battle is to
be in struggle right um and we have seen so many of our ancestors be put in these
courageously terrible situations like the fact that like i'm like my lawyer had to integrate a
school you know she had to be like the first black child at a white school i mean this woman is now in
her late 50s and she can tell you about all of it right because it's still in her like yeah i really had
to go through that you know and so so many of us like yourself have this courage in us we have this
bravery we have this um this measure of morality and we think like oh that's why i need to be in this
deleterious space because i need to like spread all of that through here but what ends up happening
is that it can corrupt you or disrupt you right because i can absolutely say that in black hollywood
i never lost my my tenacity for justice and for morale but i lost my trust in myself like because i was
overcome like it's just too much like you can't beat it right and so then you're forced if you listen
you're forced out of these spaces into places of community that you never even really knew existed
and um do you read yes oh my god do you like um do you like sci-fi or fantasy like does that
ever do you ever get into that i'm trying to break down and to read like better things because right now
it's just been like audrey lord all the essays from tony morrison and james baldwin like i sometimes
i just need something to you know okay so i'm gonna suggest a book for you it's called the fifth season
okay by n k jemisin jemisin i spell jimmy uh j-e-m-i-s-i-n okay okay thank you so this is a part
of a three book series but even the first book is really just um they call her like the the octavia
butler of our time yes and the reason i want the reason i suggest this book is because even though
it is considered like fantasy the lessons are so loud in understanding what community can look like
right and right reimagining our um reimagining what it we're reconnecting to like thinking of ourselves
as a part of a greater whole and and the understanding of like our our power and how
when we have a certain level of power we are dangerous to others that's right which is very
true it is very they can they see us as dangerous even though we can save them yeah they see us as
dangerous right so like the lead character you'll come to see but like even though she has a gift
that is a that is able to save everyone um she's seen as dangerous because that same gift is also
able to harm if it is not given the opportunity to exist like naturally if she's triggered it's a rat
so um so when you talk about your ancestors have you done any like genealogy or anything like that
no no i'm scared i'm scared of ai i'm scared of people getting my information my you know but so
i don't know where to begin with that but i need to know this is a calling yeah like i mean there are
genealogists they are black like heritage projects that use that they don't go for by your dna like they
go by archives um yeah so um they go by archives and they basically go through all of the
the mass of documents that that are here right to show us um hold on i'm gonna tell you somebody
kimberly renee so kimberly renee on instagram is a genealogist and she actually did my genealogy
and i did an episode of it on small doses uh on the podcast and she was able to find out for me you
know not only the origins of my because we just did my paternal side so we were able to find out the
origins of my paternal side and of course travel slavery and where that lies in there and that i am
very possibly a descendant of robert e lee oh yes ma'am oh lord so when people are like why are you like
that it's like because i'm fighting massa like a whole general map yeah literally oh lord i see i see
and someone in here asked can we do that ourselves at the library i mean yes if you are able to be re
if you're a researcher like that like i i feel like i don't have the knowledge of like where you get
those sources from in the ways that others do because there's like archives there's obituaries
there's um like worker records there's also um there's like all different kinds of like records
that different cities and towns have that people are able to do this um yeah but i think you know
the fact that you're even asking these questions this is is an indicator of being on a path to
where you want to be a lot of people don't ask these questions because when these questions come up
they're like ah yeah i don't want to i don't want to know i i know i everything's good here we're
good and i'm and i'm not good and i'm not good with the way that the world is going i'm not good
with not knowing my history because in order to know where you're going you need to know where you came
from and in order to know where you came from you need to know your ancestors you need to know the
people that have that that have brought you the strength that you are carrying today where am i getting
this this courage to think that this is where i need to be from you know what i'm saying i need to channel
that to figure out where i'm going next because this ain't forever and i know that i i'm uh i'm
trying to get engaged to my woman right now uh we gonna work on that real soon thank you yeah she
at work right now i can't wait to tell her about this but um you know i want to be able to to channel
those energies and i want to move on forward but i know that where i'm at career-wise right now is not
forever you know i'm also an artist play the keys you know like there are parts of me that i need to
continue to work on you i love your art there are parts of me that i that i am lacking that i am not
fulfilling that my ancestors are saying you need to get back to you to your roots to what we gave you
the gifts that we gave you yeah you know and and i can't do that when i'm fixing engines on a helicopter
so i need to i need to do something else i i am ready to leave and i'm ready to get back to me
and this was an excellent first step i can't wait to read this book i'm gonna talk to miss miss
kimberly and i'm gonna see where i can go from there because uh you know this is this is an amazing
amazing first step i'm just so grateful for you and your platform and and being able to reach out
to me today this it truly means a lot to me oh man oh man oh thank you so much oh boy thank you so
much golly willikers uh you keep going on this journey and i wish you the best and let me tell
you something some people just got it you know what i'm saying like you just got it you already know
you know what i mean oh dude yo one more thing you you had a show in philly i went to go see you in
philly you was uh you was performing you did a comedy show back in the day and there was this
uh psychiatrist that that i really spoke to and we both followed you very well so i just want to
give a shout out um to miss uh dr latisha uh she worked at fairmont behavioral health she is amazing
and i appreciate her for being able to uh take me to a place to see you in real life and wait wait was
i in a comedy club or a theater it was a theater was there a rug on the ground yeah it was
like 20 23. i remember talking about um i had a makeup artist in atlanta who had showed up at
7 a.m with high boots on i just remember that bit because i remember being like how is it how do you
have on a stiletto tall boot like did you come straight from the club what happened i was like man
um but that was that was a great show philly is always a great audience like i love philly philly
is always a great audience philly has the best rappers okay nobody argue with me about it philly
also has the best drummers oh come on quest come on actually not even quest because quest will tell
you he's not the best um life is an incredible band leader yeah he's a drummer i mean but like there's
cats in philly who is really just tanning actually one of them just passed away so rest in peace to
dale robinson um but listen i you know i've had bands for a long time when i was doing music and
you're always like i need a philly drummer there you go there you go i need a philly drummer they
gonna tear it up you're like i need something that has like a boom and they're like oh you mean like this
it's and then and then hit it for you yes and then your spirit go a different go like yes yes
so shout out to the cannons um so you know shout out to the philly johns and all of that
you already know all right enjoy the rest of your evening and your journey and congratulations
pre-congratulations on the engagement thank you thank you i'll see you soon all right showing much
love i'll see y'all later all right bye bye yeah is this little project that we're doing here what would
your ancestors say i mean also like why why did she come on and we were the same person i love it
it well that is tonight's show and um how dope would it be if this was like an actual show right
one thing about amanda is she gonna make a show okay think about me i'm gonna make a show i can
make a show out of anything i know how to make a show okay miss debbie um so reminder that if you
haven't gotten your tickets to see what would the ancestors say my live stream and book release on
november 8th please do so show your girls some love go and get your tickets at amandaseals.com
and um you know just know that you are supporting a real one okay you're supporting a real one like
this is not something that i'm doing like you can't do this kind of work just willy-nilly like
this is the type of work that comes from the soul and the spirit so i appreciate y'all and we will be
back tomorrow night at 8 p.m eastern will we i may not be back tomorrow night it may be
actually no yes yes yes tomorrow night we will be i may not be able to do friday night but tomorrow
night we'll be back at 8 p.m eastern someone said what would robert e lee say
robert e lee would say you effing niggers like that's what he would say that's what he would say
and i would be like um so again if you're just joining us want to remind you that i will be in
dc on the national mall on sunday between noon and 1 30 doing a special presentation of what would the
ancestors say and talking to the people as a part of a teaching that's happening all day with other
scholars and intellectuals and professors etc so it's going to be a really really beautiful time
and i'm gonna be out there and y'all gonna be out there and um i'm gonna be wearing something pretty
cool because i never leave the house so when i do i'm like y'all are gonna get something cool
all right so i will see you guys and again if you are in la on november 8th make sure to go get your
tickets so that i can see you in person and you can get your book signed in person at what would
the ancestors say and we will be filming at kev on stage studios so shout to kev on stage and um
shout to transit pictures production company we did this last year and we're doing it again
everybody have a beautiful night and look out for my book tour dates coming soon